1799 Candy Lane, Carbondale, Illinois 62902 | C: 618-412-0081 | jkledbetter6070@gmail.com

### **OBJECTIVE**

Seeking employment in the Geographical Information Technologies field. Over the last several years I have honed my skills in geography and environmental resources with a focus in GIS. Proficient with ESRI GIS software and remote sensing equipment.

### SKILLS & ABILITIES

- Adept conflict resolution skills
- Resourceful project management
- Proficient with Geographical Information System software Including: ESRI software, Rstudio, GIT/GITHub, Openrefine
- Capable with Remote Sensing Equipment Including: Trimble equipment, Google Earth Engine
- Goal-oriented
- Effective communicator
- Motivated team player

## **EDUCATION**

## University of Oklahoma

Projected August 2022

Master of Science in Geography and Environmental Sustainability Focus on Geographical Information Technologies

# Southern Illinois University at Carbondale

December 2020

Bachelor of Science in Geography and Environmental Resources Focus on Geographical Information Science

# Southern Illinois University at Carbondale

December 2007

Bachelor of Arts in Administration of Justice
Minor in Environmental Science.

#### EXPERIENCE

## Police Officer | Southern Illinois Airport Authority Police

December 2018 - March 2021

- Maintain training records of all active officers
- Maintain heightened level of situational awareness during shift hours
- Network with outside agencies to share information such as criminal events
- Assess criminal and non-criminal situations and mitigate outcomes to best serve the public
- Assess, respond and mitigate emergencies on and off Airport Property

#### EXPERIENCE

# Director and Firearms Instructor | Shawnee Tactical Solutions

May 2011 - February 2021

- Maintain federal and state licensure
- Maintain active liability insurance on all instructors
- Maintain training records for all instructors
- Facilitate training cycles and write all course curriculum
- Instruct students in personal security tactics with and without firearms

### EXPERIENCE

# Environmental Impact Specialist | Maka, LLC

August 2013 – December 2015

- Site survey and planning of watershed management
- Planning and implementation of wastewater runoff from gob piles
- Implementation of new gob pile "bag" reclamation project
- Operation of heavy machinery as needed

### REFERENCES

Andrew Misker, Shawnee Tactical Solutions, LLC

618-201-9148 <u>amisker0713@gmail.com</u>

Justin Schoof, PHD, Southern Illinois University, Carbondale

618-453-6019 jschoof@siu.edu